Simone Donohue

I am originally from the Gold Coast but I relocated to Europe in 2013 to expand my horizons, gain experience, and develop my skills. This year I have relocated to Melbourne to continue working in production and postproduction and to expand my knowledge and skills gained overseas.

409/12 Trenerry Crescent
Abbotsford, 3067
(+61) 411 521 214
simonedonohue.com
donohue.simone@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/simone
_donohue-75ab4271

EXPERIENCE

72andSunny, Amsterdam — *Studio Coordinator/Post Producer*

March 2016 - October 2016

After freelancing for several months in the same role I took the position of Studio coordinator at 72andSunny, Over my time working in this role I performed 4 main functions.

Firstly, I planned the schedules and resources for the work in the agencies internal design and video-editing studio along with the Studio Manager. Managing the workload of 2 full time designers and an editor/animator and up to 20 rotating freelancers on between 5 and 15 simultaneous projects.

Secondly, I produced projects in a post-production/adaptations phase predominantly for our client Google. I produced adaptations for the Google App, Gboard and Chromecast campaigns for up to 18 EU markets.

Thirdly, I was the Studio's asset manager, managing the assets/media files of the servers, archive and post production workflow.

Additionally I edited a variety of projects both as an assistant editor and independently. I edited on projects such as the Cannes Awards Case Studies for Samsung and Google; Market research videos, and internal presentations for the agency.

Freelance, Amsterdam — Editor/Producer

June 2015 - March 2016

As a freelance junior producer and video editor I worked primarily in corporate and commercial film production and online content creation.

I work with agencies and production companies; 72andSunny, Flickering Wall, and BRAND-and-STORY; for clients such as Google, ING Bank and Akzo Nobel and Eriks.

SKILLS

Communication —

Excellent spoken and written communication skills.

Practical — Organised, fast learner, thrives under pressure.

Production — Budgeting, scheduling, sourcing; personnel, locations, transport, etc. Experience with high end advertising post production workflow

Software — Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Photoshop, Avid Media Composer, Adobe Photoshop, MS Office Suite, Google Drive, Docs, Sheets and Slides

EDUCATION

Griffith Film School,South Bank, Brisbane —
Bachelor of Film and
Screen Media Production

February 2012 - November 2012

Griffith University, Gold Coast — Bachelor of Arts

February 2011 - November 2011

Flickering Wall, Amsterdam — Assistant Producer/Media Manager

January 2014 - June 2015

Primarily working with senior producers and Independently to produce corporate and commercial films for various Dutch and international clients. The secondary part of my role was the Media/Asset manager for the company where I was responsible for the day to day maintenance of video servers and archiving of creative material.

Flickering Wall, Amsterdam — Production Internship

July 2013 - December 2013

Worked closely with producers to put in place all assets for film productions, including but not limited to: hiring crew, searching for locations, buying props, hiring transport and equipment, booking flights and accommodation, runner on shoots, submitting films to various film festivals, creating and amending production documents.

Additionally I partnered with the Office Manager in a general office support capacity; answering and forwarding calls, ordering lunch/preparing lunch room, catering for guests, running errands

During the internship I was trained in Media/Video Asset Management and took on an assisting role in the post-production department. Where I expanded my editing capabilities while working on edits for internal and online use.

REFERENCES

Tanya Funnell, Studio Manager at 72andSunny — Direct Manager

tanya.funnell@72andsunny.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/tanya-funnell-31a97024

Vargo Bawits, Head of Production at Flickering wall — *Direct Manager*

+31 6 38067518

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vargoba wits